[
  {
    "question": "The indipendent region of Macao (in China), used to be until 1999 a colony of which other country?",
    "answer": "Portugal",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Half a point for all the 12 most common elements in the human body.",
    "answer": "​​Oxygen, hydrogen, nitrogen, carbon, calcium, and phosphorus, sulfur, potassium, sodium, chlorine, and magnesium",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which country does the northest university in the world belong?",
    "answer": "Norway, Tromso",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many edges does an hendecagon has?",
    "answer": "11",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year did Michael Jackson died?",
    "answer": "June 25th, 2009",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which color takes his name from a famous French liqueur?",
    "answer": "Chartreuse",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2026 the famous Sagrada Familia will be completed. Which Pope did it consecrated it?",
    "answer": "Benedetto XVI",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which party won the last National Elections in Luxembourg?",
    "answer": "CSV",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city can you find the Smithsonian Museum of of History and Natural History?",
    "answer": "Washington",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
{
    "question": "Which musicist and actor, belonging to 30 second to Mars, recently climbed the Empire State Building to announce his new album? [Jared Leto]",
    "answer": "Jared Leto",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cosimo, Piero and Lorenzo were the first names of three generations of which family? [De Medici]",
    "answer": "De Medici",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many theses did Martin Luther write?",
    "answer": "56",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "half a point for each of the 10 countries the Danube runs through or touches.",
    "answer": "Germany, Austria, Slovakia, Hungary, Croatia, Serbia, Romania, Moldova, Ukraine, Bulgaria",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fossil records shows that dogs were the first animal to be domesticated by humans. Which was the second?",
    "answer": "Goat, Pig was third",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which artist is currently undergoing a world tour with an estimated commercial value of 5 billions dollars?",
    "answer": "Taylor Swift",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which gene editing technique was discovered/invented in 2013?",
    "answer": "CRISPR",
    "tags": "general knowledge",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which famous circuit you can find the series of corners called \"the corkscrew\"?",
    "answer": "Laguna Seca",
    "tags": "sport",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which football player won the 2023 ballon d'or?",
    "answer": "Lionel Messi",
    "tags": "sport",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which city/country will the 2024 Tour de France start?",
    "answer": "Florence",
    "tags": "sport",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which sport can you find quaffles and bludger?",
    "answer": "Quiddich",
    "tags": "sport",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Novak Djokovich broke this month his own record for number of Master's won. How many are they?",
    "answer": "40, second is Nadal with 36",
    "tags": "sport",
    "date": "2023-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Simba mean, in Swahili?",
    "answer": "Lion",
    "tags": "movies",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which French city is Joanne D'Arc originally from?",
    "answer": "Domrémy",
    "tags": "movies",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which American city is famous for his Witcher and burning the witches?",
    "answer": "Salem",
    "tags": "movies",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Number od movies of Leonardo Di Caprio and Robert de Niro with Martis Scorsese",
    "answer": "Leo 6 + 1 mini movie and Bob 10 + 1 short",
    "tags": "movies",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "On October 23rd 2023 Matthew Perry died. Which former lover of Matthew Perry had her birthday on exactly the same day?",
    "answer": "Julia Roberts",
    "tags": "TV",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which age was Matthew Perry when he died?",
    "answer": "54",
    "tags": "TV",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "At the age of 57, which actor (hint: from Greys anatomy) has been nominated the sexiest man alive by the magazine People?",
    "answer": "Patrick Dempsey",
    "tags": "TV",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is sheldon always knocking 3 times before opening doors?",
    "answer": "To allow people to put their pants on",
    "tags": "TV",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whith 3 Ph.D.s, 7 master degrees and a total of more than 50 years of Harvard studies, which cartoon has the most overeducated creators in history?",
    "answer": "Futurama",
    "tags": "TV",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "What's the name of the famous lover of Sherlock Holmes?",
    "answer": "Irene Adler",
    "tags": "TV",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which movie did Stanley Kubrick learned to stop worrying and love the bomb?",
    "answer": "Doctor Strangelove",
    "tags": "movies",
    "date": "2024-11-10"
  }
]

